Rachel Sproule Interaction Designer

PERSONAL PROFILE

An Interaction designer currently specialising in UX Design, UI Design and illustration. A hard working and self motivated creator who enjoys applying a unique style and creative flare to all projects and tasks. Someone who is highly committed with a passion for learning and enjoys working as part of a team unit, collaborating with fellow creators and mentoring others. Through studying a full time degree in interaction design. I constantly strive to build upon my knowledge and develop new skills as a designer.

WORK EXPERIENCE

BARISTA AND WAITRESS (Present)

Rosetta Cafe

- Trained in serving coffee, taking orders, communicating with kitchen staff and motivating co-workers.
- Responsibilities in maintaining the storefront, deep cleaning all surface areas. cashing up and key-holding.
- Increased overall sales and customer satisfaction rate within the store.

FLOOR STAFF (2019)

lamm Omagh

- Developed skills in waitressing, food safety and customer service
- Performed duties such as food preparation and till operation.
- Managed and maintained the kitchen and storefront, increased overall store cleanliness
- Coordinated with 15+ kitchen staff members to conduct a daily deep clean of all surface areas

COURSE REPRESENTATIVE (2018-2019)

Ulster University

- Conducted meetings with students to help identify and address issues within the course.
- Coordinated Staff-Student Course Committee meetings with the Course Director.
- Collaborated with senior members of staff and helped to resolve conflict.
- Boosted overall student satisfaction rate.

FREELANCE WORK (2017-2018)

Self Employed

- Commissioned work in Graphic Design and Fine Art.
- Gained valuable knowledge in self promotion, curation, brand development and pricing.
- Worked with and advised clients on a one to one basis.
- Produced high quality work for over 50 different clients.

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- Through Full time academic study, I have gained skills in UI Design, UX Design, Digital Prototyping, User Research, Usability testing, Brand Design, Graphic Design, Illustration, Iconography and Coding (HTML5, CSS and CSS Grid).
- Proficient in multiple software programs such as Photoshop, Illustrator, Sketch, Invision, Marvel, Brackets and Github Desktop.
- Through work experience, I have developed skills in customer service, project management, commercial awareness, teamwork, multitasking, time management, attention to detail, communication, self motivation and problem solving.

22 RATHGAR STREET, LISBURN ROAD, BELFAST, BT9 7GD

• TWITTER: @sproule_c PHONE: 07794794111

• EMAIL: email@rachelsproule.me

EDUCATION

BA Hons Interaction Design, Ulster University Belfast (2018-2022)

Interaction Design Fundamentals (IXD101), Communication Design (IXD102), Exploring Identity (IXD103), Imaging and Data Visualisation (IXD104), Designing with Content (IXD301), Creative Entrepreneurship (IXD302)

BA Hons Foundation Art and Design, **Ulster University Belfast** (2017-2018)

Drawing in practice (AAD009), Introducing studio practise (AADO10). Contextual research and understanding (AAD011), Exploring studio practise (AAD012)

A Levels (CCEA), Omagh Academy

(2015-2017)

Art and Design (A*) Geography (A) Music (B)

GCSE (CCEA), Omagh Academy

(2013-2015)

Maths (A*) Art and Design (A*) Geography (A*) Music (A) Spanish (A) English (AB) Science (AB) Performing Arts (C)

ADDITIONAL ACHIEVEMENTS

Fermanagh and Omagh Young Achievers Award in Art and Design (2018)

CCEA Celebrating Excellence Awards in Art and Design (2017)

R.A Simpson Cup in Art and Design (Omagh Academy) (2017)

Graham Cup in Music (Omagh Academy) (2017)

CCEA True Colours Exhibition (2015)

REFERENCES

KYLE BOYD

Interaction Design Lecturer, Ulster University ka.boyd@ulster.ac.uk

PAUL MCCORMACK

Interaction Design Course Director, Ulster University

p.mccormack@ulster.ac.uk